Bijaya Ghimire

Tarakeshwor-4, Kathmandu | ☐ +977 9846936320 | \(\sigma_{vijay.gh}74@gmail.com \) \(\sigma_{www.linkedin.com/in/bijay-gh/\) ⊕bijay-gh.github.io/

Summary

Enthusiastic, passionate, self-motivated Data Science and Machine learning learner having little experience of few machines learning work. I am very interested in learning about and working in the field of artificial intelligence, data science, and computer vision.

Education

Pashchimanchal Campus, IOE, TU

Lamachaur-16, Pokhara, Nepal

Bachelor in Electronics, Communication and Information Engineering

2018-2023

Coursework: C, OOP, Data Structure and Algorithm, Applied Mathematics, Microprocessor, Computer Graphics, Probability and Statistics, AI, Data Mining, Big Data Technology, Remote Sensing.

National School of Sciences (NIST)

Lainchour-16, Kathmandu, Nepal

Science Stream [GPA: 3.33/4]

2016-2018

Coursework: Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry and Biology

Experience

Omdena Palo Alto California, USA

Junior ML Engineer (Remote)

Combating Misinformation with Data Science and AI

Feb 2023-Present

- Source through different Nepali fact check organization to collect a dataset of verified fake news and Carryout data processing and data analytics to understand the distribution of misinformation.
- Apply Data Science, Data Engineering and Machine Learning develop an API to identify if a particular post has already been classified as misinformation.

Junior ML Engineer (Remote)

Creating a Rice Disease Classifier

Mar 2023-Present

Aim to deploy a deep learning model through a website or mobile application that will identify different rice diseases by simply uploading a photo of a rice crop.

Vulcan Gaming Lamachaur-16, Pokhara May 2022 - Dec 2022

Game Data Analytics

- Work with game log data to retrieve and analyses player and team performance matrices in game.
- Assist forecasts and predictions for different decision scenarios which can be used to produce commentary and reviews of games.
- Compiling an event report with specifics, including an analysis and visualization of player and team performance.

Broadcasting and Data Entry

Mar 2021 - Apr 2022

- Entering players, matches, event data from source documents and reviewing data for deficiencies or errors, correcting any incompatibilities and checking output.
- Manage the startup & setup process broadcast & live streaming equipment, including bringing all broadcast signals live and pushing them to all relevant distribution channels.

Pashchimanchal Campus

Ball Tracking and 3D Coordinate Extraction

Jun 2022 – May 2023

On behalf of the final year project (thesis) of undergraduate, I had developed cricket ball tracking system and assist to visualize the trajectory to do sport analysis and decision review

Overspeed Detection and ANPR

Dec 2021- May 2022

Integrating Automatic number plate recognition system with speed detection to detect over speeding vehicles.

South Asian Games 2019

Pokhara Stadium, Pokhara

Broadcast Engineer | NK Media Ventures Pvt Ltd

Dec 2019(10 days)

Live Streaming of South Asian Games 2019 held in Pokhara, Nepal. The games included, Women's football, Handball, Badminton, Archery.

- Configured and developed a full system for broadcast of all South Asian Games events.
- Significantly increased user engagement on the platform and reduced latency

Shree Gyan Jyoti Higher Secondary School

Airkot-3, Gorkha Aug 2018 – Oct 2018

- Taught science to students in grades 6 to 9, fostering curiosity, critical thinking, and a love for the subject.
- Developed and implemented innovative lesson plans incorporating technology tools and hands-on activities to foster student engagement and improve learning outcomes.

Activities & Extracurriculars

Participation, Richter's Predictor: Modeling Earthquake Damage, Drivendata

Apr 2023

Predict the damage grade of the building that was hit by the 2015 Nepal earthquake.

Applied Data Science Lab, WorldQuant University

Mar 2023

• Complete a series of end-to-end data science projects, building the wrangling, analysis, model-building, and communication skills

Certifications

Science Teacher

TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques Specialization, DeepLearning.AI Coursera	2023
Applied Data Science with Python Specialization, University of Michigan Coursera	2023
Machine Learning, Stanford University, DeepLearning.AI Coursera	2022
Python for Everybody Specialization, University of Michigan Coursera	2022

Skills & Interests

Languages: Nepali-Fluent, English- Fluent, Hindi-Good

Programming, tools and library: Python, C++, TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy,

OpenCV, NLTK, Seaborn, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB, Jupyter Notebook.

Interest: Data Science, Computer Vision, Teaching, Research,